<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 16:03:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://89.147.111.130:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Decent Portable Terminal Windows</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/creating-a-decent-portable-terminal-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 16:03:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/creating-a-decent-portable-terminal-windows/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Decent Portable Terminal Windows Preamble Directions for creating a portable build of Alacritty with a portable set of busybox tools and windows CLI applications.&#xA;The goal is to have a good terminal emulator that can be ran on any system. I prefer avoiding WSL and Cygwin.&#xA;Directory Structure Alacritty is the terminal emulator. In the same folder is a RUNME.bat that configures the environment and sources the alacritty.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operazione: Vita Gentile</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/peter/vita-gentile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 16:53:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/peter/vita-gentile/</guid>
      <description>Operazione: Vita Gentile Preamble This contains bits of my life I would rather not have saved in running memory. I hope some of the things in this list can be inspiring or useful to you \()/&#xA;Heading Phone My cell phone number was ported to Google Voice to remove the dependence on my phone. There is currently nothing on my device that can&amp;#39;t be accessed from my computer.&#xA;This provides the Freedom to have any cellular plan or provider I&amp;#39;d like.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running Ollama Portably</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/uncategorized/running-ollama-portably/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 11:59:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/uncategorized/running-ollama-portably/</guid>
      <description>Running Ollama Portably Preamble Directions for creating a portable installation of Ollama. The LLM files will be stored in the same folder as the binaries and sourced automatically&#xA;Creating the portable installation Install Ollama Normally Install Ollama using this link. The default installation folder will be %localappdata%\Programs\Ollama&#xA;https://ollama.com/download&#xA;Creating a batch script Create a file named &amp;#34;START_OLLAMA.bat&amp;#34; in %localappdata%\Programs\Ollama&#xA;@echo off title Ollama Portable set OLLAMA_ORIGINS=* set OLLAMA_HOST=127.0.0.1 set userprofile=%cd%\data set localappdata=%cd%\data\AppData\Local start cmd /k &amp;#34;%cd%\ollama.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs With Directional Google Calendar Sync</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/emacs/emacs-with-bidirectional-google-calendar-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 19:00:38 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/emacs/emacs-with-bidirectional-google-calendar-sync/</guid>
      <description>Emacs With Directional Google Calendar Sync Preamble Directions to setup the org-gcal package for bidirectional Google Calendar Sync. Emacs 30 was used. The AppImage can be located here: LINK&#xA;Calendar Sync Create a new app on the Google Developer Console Install org-gcal Add your API keys Sync Calendar The guide on the Kidd&amp;#39;s README is incredibly detailed. I&amp;#39;ll be copying most of it and including the solutions that left me with a working system.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating an Offline Debian Mirror Repository</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/linux/creating-an-offline-debian-mirror-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 22:54:06 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/linux/creating-an-offline-debian-mirror-repository/</guid>
      <description>Creating an Offline Debian Mirror Repository Preamble Directions for creating a fully functional offline Debian mirror with most, but not all, packages available.&#xA;Creating the offline mirror Overview Install xr09&amp;#39;s mirror script Download Packages to folder Generate package index list Use the mirror Mirror Script Clone this repo: https://github.com/xr09/debian-mini-repo/blob/master/cron-debmirror&#xA;Edit the script and change the REPOS_DIR variable in the mirror.sh file. This should be the local path that will store the packages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs with Mu4e and Multiple Gmail Accounts</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/emacs/emacs-with-mu4e-and-multiple-gmail-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:53:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/emacs/emacs-with-mu4e-and-multiple-gmail-accounts/</guid>
      <description>Emacs with Mu4e and Multiple Gmail Accounts Preamble Documented steps I take to setup Mu4e with two Gmail accounts. This page will contain the directions for using app password authentication. It will be updated when XOAUTH2.0 is required.&#xA;Installation Gmail I&amp;#39;m using app passwords while they still last. Eventually this section will contain information on setting up XOAUTH 2.0 when app passwords are fully phased out.&#xA;Two email accounts will be added to Mu4e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Migrate Wiki.js to Another Server</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/linux/migrate-wiki.js-to-another-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 07:54:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/linux/migrate-wiki.js-to-another-server/</guid>
      <description>Migrate Wiki.js to Another Server Preamble Documented steps I took to migrate Wiki.JS from one server to another. The original instance was running on docker. The new instance is on an LXC container.&#xA;Migrating Steps Overview The original server runs WikiJS through docker. One container contains the PostgresDB and the other contains the node server&#xA;New server will be running WikiJS natively&#xA;Exporting the database on old server From the old server, run the following command to dump the database to a file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corebooting Thinkpad X220 With CH341A Programmer</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/linux/corebooting-thinkpad-x220-with-ch341a-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 09:35:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/linux/corebooting-thinkpad-x220-with-ch341a-programmer/</guid>
      <description>Summary of page This isn&amp;#39;t going to be a walkthrough of corebooting your Thinkpad X220. These are the steps you need to get the flasher working and connected to your system&#xA;Fyi: My host system is Windows 11 and a virtual machine with USB redirection was used to flash the system&#xA;I exported the factory default ROMS to my PC&#xA;Step 1 - Buy the flasher I purchased the following CH341A programmer with the clip from Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic CHKDSK Scans Using Powershell &amp; Email Alerts</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/automating-chkdsk-scans-using-powershell-with-email-alerts-for-rmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 20:44:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/automating-chkdsk-scans-using-powershell-with-email-alerts-for-rmm/</guid>
      <description>Automatic CHKDSK Scans Using Powershell &amp;amp; Email Alerts Preamble Directions for using a Powershell script I wrote to schedule automatic CHKDSK scans whenever an NTFS or DISK error appears in the event log.&#xA;If corruption occurs more than once per week, an email is sent out to your desired address. SFC &amp;amp; DISM scans are scheduled for 10PM. CHKDSKs on the corrupt drive are scheduled for 12AM&#xA;It can be run through a scheduled task locally or deployed as a response policy in remote management software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adding Bitwarden to the Pinephone Pro</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/linux/adding-bitwarden-to-the-pinephone-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 21:20:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/linux/adding-bitwarden-to-the-pinephone-pro/</guid>
      <description>Adding Bitwarden to the Pinephone Pro Preamble Directions on adding Bitwarden on the Pinephone Pro on PMOS PHOSH. It relies the Firefox Bitwarden extension and a .desktop file that&amp;#39;s used to open it.&#xA;Bitwarden Setup Adding the extension Reduce your screen scaling to the lowest available in the PHOSH settings. This prevents rendering glitches.&#xA;Open Firefox Install the Bitwarden extension from https://addons.mozilla.org Press &amp;#34;C-b&amp;#34; to open the firefox sidebar. Use the drop down to switch from the bookmarks view to Bitwarden.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emacs EWW Hacks</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/emacs/emacs-eww-hacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 08:32:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/emacs/emacs-eww-hacks/</guid>
      <description>Emacs EWW Hacks Preamble Collection of emacs snippets to enhance the eww experience.&#xA;Hack list Simple Styling (setq browse-url-browser-function &amp;#39;eww-browse-url) ; Use eww as the default browser (setq shr-use-fonts nil) ; No special fonts (setq shr-use-colors nil) ; No colours (setq shr-indentation 4) ; Left-side margin (setq shr-width 70) ; Fold text to 70 columns (setq eww-search-prefix &amp;#34;https://google.com/search?q=&amp;#34;) ; Use another engine for searching Rename EWW Buffers to Website Names (setq eww-auto-rename-buffer t) Force EWW to open new buffers by default Normally EWW only runs as a single buffer, similar to Eshell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Default Wireless Password to TG1672G Routers</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/uncategorized/getting-the-default-wireless-password-to-tg1672g-routers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 14:09:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/uncategorized/getting-the-default-wireless-password-to-tg1672g-routers/</guid>
      <description>Finding the Default Wireless Password to TG1672G Routers Preamble Directions for finding the default wireless password on TG1672G routers. These routers have a predictable scheme for the &amp;#34;randomly&amp;#34; generated password. The router is commonly used in Central America with locations using TIGO as their ISP.&#xA;Cracking the code Password schema This pattern is used for the password. Stupid, I know.&#xA;TG1672G&amp;lt;FIRST BYTE OF BSSID NIC SPECIFIC&amp;gt;&amp;lt;LAST FOUR OF SSID&amp;gt; Getting the password Without being connected to a wireless network, run the following in a Windows Command Prompt as administrator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Bad Blocks NTFS Filesystems</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/simulating-bad-blocks-on-ntfs-filesystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 19:02:59 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/simulating-bad-blocks-on-ntfs-filesystems/</guid>
      <description>Simulating Bad Blocks on NTFS Filesystems Preamble Directions for simulating a file system corruption error on an NTFS drive on a Windows host system. This is useful when you are testing tools that require this error exist.&#xA;Simulating Corruption https://github.com/jamersonpro/ntfsmarkbad&#xA;Creating the test environment Create the folder for our demo environment&#xA;mkdir BadBlocktest cd BadBlockTest Download the NtfsMarkBad tool&#xA;Invoke-WebRequest -Uri &amp;#34;https://github.com/jamersonpro/ntfsmarkbad/releases/download/v0.0.2/NtfsMarkBad.exe&amp;#34; -Outfile &amp;#34;NtfsMarkBad.exe&amp;#34; -UseBasicParsing Create a virtual hard disk file</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloning a Bios Boot Drive to Disimilar Hardware with UEFI</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/cloning-a-bios-boot-drive-to-disimilar-hardware-with-uefi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 15:51:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/cloning-a-bios-boot-drive-to-disimilar-hardware-with-uefi/</guid>
      <description>Cloning a Bios Boot Drive to Disimilar Hardware with UEFI Preamble Documented steps for cloning a drive to another computer. The source computer is running an MBR partition table. The target computer is of completely different hardware and runs UEFI *Cloning the drive Overview I had a clone an old Dell Machine to a new Dell Optiplex SFF 7010. The problem was the new computer had an NVME drive with storage controller drivers that weren&amp;#39;t even in the Windows 11 installation media.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Merging HyperV Snapshots With Powershell</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/merging-hyperv-snapshots-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 13:40:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/merging-hyperv-snapshots-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Merging HyperV Snapshots With Powershell Preamble Directions for how to merge multiple HyperV snapshot differencing files.&#xA;Merging the snapshot Identify your child avhdx file Get-VM | Get-VMHardDiskDrive | Select VMName,Path VMName Path ------ ---- Domain Controller D:\VMs\Domain Controller_1023082130.avhdx Installing the Hyper-V Powershell CMDLETS Enable-WindowsOptionalFeature -Online -FeatureName Microsoft-Hyper-V-Management-PowerShell Merge the AVHDX Make sure your VM is turned off. The Merge-VHD operation requires the avhdx file be offline.&#xA;The destination path will be the snapshot or VHDX file that you want to merge into.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik Creating a Client to Site VPN With Wireguard</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/mikrotik/mikrotik-creating-a-client-to-site-vpn-with-wireguard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 13:00:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/mikrotik/mikrotik-creating-a-client-to-site-vpn-with-wireguard/</guid>
      <description>Mikrotik Creating a Client to Site VPN With Wireguard Preamble Directions for setting up a Wireguard client-to-site server on a Mikrotik. This is done using the command line from SSH or Winbox.&#xA;Server Configuration Create Wireguard interface Add a new wireguard interface and give it the name &amp;#34;Wireguard1&amp;#34; The listening port is set to the default port number that the wireguard devs intended. The MTU value is default to what Mikrotik auto-fills</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik Securing Router With Firewall</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/mikrotik/mikrotik-securing-router-with-firewall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 12:55:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/mikrotik/mikrotik-securing-router-with-firewall/</guid>
      <description>Mikrotik Securing Router With Firewall Preamble Documented are firewall rules to enable after resetting your Mikrotik firewall. It will provide good baseline security.&#xA;Securing the firewall Fresh Start Incase you mess up or want a fresh start, run these two commands to clear all firewall rules and address lists. Note that if you re-run the command to add a filter, it&amp;#39;ll either error out or duplicate if it already exists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mikrotik Setup Dynamically Changing IP With No-IP Api</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/mikrotik/mikrotik-setup-dynamically-changing-ip-with-no-ip-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 12:51:42 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/mikrotik/mikrotik-setup-dynamically-changing-ip-with-no-ip-api/</guid>
      <description>Mikrotik Setup Dynamically Changing IP With No-IP Api Preamble Directions for how to configure dynamic DNS on a mikrotik. It leverages the No-IP REST API and the mikrotik&amp;#39;s built-in scripting environment.&#xA;Dynamically Updating the IP Code Use the System&amp;gt;Scripts page and create a new script with this code. Change the variables under the Script Settings block. Set the name of the script to &amp;#34;NoIP&amp;#34;&#xA;Source Page&#xA;##############Script Settings################## :local NOIPUser &amp;#34;USERNAME&amp;#34; :local NOIPPass &amp;#34;PASSWORD&amp;#34; :local WANInter &amp;#34;ether1&amp;#34; :local NOIPDomain &amp;#34;NO-IP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows Server Creating and Viewing a Storport Trace</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/windows-server-creating-and-viewing-a-storport-trace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:24:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/windows/windows-server-creating-and-viewing-a-storport-trace/</guid>
      <description>Windows Server Creating and Viewing a Storport Trace Preamble Site under construction. This page has to be re-read and remembered. I believe this is to use a excel template to parse a storport trace. It will calculate the latency of SAS drives though I think the output was weirdly documented along with the template.&#xA;Tracing Creating a StorPort trace using logman.exe LOGMAN.EXE is CLI utility for creating data collector sets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qemu Windows Xp Fix Smb Not Working</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/qemu/qemu-windows-xp-fix-smb-not-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:14:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/qemu/qemu-windows-xp-fix-smb-not-working/</guid>
      <description>Qemu Windows Xp Fix Smb Not Working Preamble Directions on fixing SMB on Windows XP system. The environment is running under Debian + Qemu&#xA;Resolution Explanation of fix SMB 1.0 has to be enabled if you try to pass a local folder as an smb share to a WinXP Qemu VM. Qemu creates the temporary file /tmp/smb.conf that holds the configurations for samba. The values of this are hard coded and can only be modified after it&amp;#39;s automatically created by Qemu.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qemu Windows Xp Installation</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/qemu/qemu-windows-xp-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:13:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/qemu/qemu-windows-xp-installation/</guid>
      <description>Qemu Windows Xp Installation Preamble Installation Dependencies Windows XP ISO (archive.org) Virtio Floppy Image (fedorapeople.org) qemu &amp;amp; spice-gtk (installed via apt-get) Installing Windows XP Product Key: MRX3F-47B9T-2487J-KWKMF-RPWBY&#xA;Here&amp;#39;s the shell script to start the installation. Windows XP will automatically search through the virtio.vfd floppy image when locating the storage drivers. That floppy image has all the drivers your networking, virtual display, virtio, etc. Mouse input and networking won&amp;#39;t work until after you&amp;#39;re logged in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qemu Mount Virtual Images</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/qemu/qemu-mount-virtual-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:11:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/qemu/qemu-mount-virtual-images/</guid>
      <description> Mounting the image apt-get install -y libguestfs-tools # Mounting guestmount -a windows.qcow2 /mnt/ # Mounting read-only mode guestmount -a windows.qcow2 /mnt/ --ro # Unmount guestunmount /mnt </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qemu Chroot Into a Different Architecture</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/qemu/qemu-chroot-into-a-different-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:10:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/qemu/qemu-chroot-into-a-different-architecture/</guid>
      <description>Qemu Chroot Into a Different Architecture Preamble Directions on using the qemu-user-static package to chroot into a system using emulation. This uses the qemu binaries on the host system to emulate the chroot system.&#xA;Setting up the chroot Preparing the chroot environment Mount the system you&amp;#39;re going to chroot into.&#xA;mount /dev/sdb2 /mnt mount /dev/sdb1 /mnt/boot Package Installation Install the following packages on the host&#xA;The emulation binaries will be placed in /usr/bin/qemu-*-static.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Troubleshooting Common Issues</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-troubleshooting-common-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:06:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-troubleshooting-common-issues/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Troubleshooting Common Issues Preamble A list of issues I&amp;#39;ve experienced first hand with the Pinebook Pro and resolutions.&#xA;Break/Fix Powerkey shuts off machine The powerkey is not in the most ideal locations. Edit /etc/systemd/logind.conf and change &amp;#34;HandlePowerKey=poweroff&amp;#34; to &amp;#34;HandlePowerKey=ignore&amp;#34;&#xA;Can&amp;#39;t boot at all after flashing EMMC You could either use an emmc to usb adapter to reflash your EMMC (LAME). You could use your official pine64 UART cable to see if you could fix the problem that way (EH).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Setting Up Zram</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-setting-up-zram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:06:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-setting-up-zram/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Setting Up Zram Preamble ZRAM is essentially compressed memory. Your system uses some of it&amp;#39;s CPU cycles to compress redundant data into a reserved area of your ram. Think of it as swap space, but without writing to your drive.&#xA;This is how to enable zram on ALARM/Manjaro ARM&#xA;Enabling ZRAM Checking if ZRAM is supported $ insmod | grep zram Output: zram ????? ? If you get similar results, zram should be supported.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Write to Spit Flash</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-write-to-spi-flash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:03:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-write-to-spi-flash/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Write to Spit Flash Preamble Directions for flashing a custom bootloader to internal Pinebook Pro&amp;#39;s SPI Flash chip. This makes it it unnecessary to have boot code on the emmc or microsd, enabling full NVME boot. NVME boot extremely is hit or miss.&#xA;Be prepared to recover your broken SPI flash if an error occurs. When a binary is written to the SPI flash, the SPI flash will be what chooses which drives to boot from.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Use Nvme as Root</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-use-nvme-as-root/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:02:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-use-nvme-as-root/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Use Nvme as Root Preamble Directions on using the Pinebook Pro&amp;#39;s NVME as a root partition and the EMMC as&#xA;Moving root partitions Assumptions You have an NVME drive installed and formatted with a single EXT4 partition Running Manjaro Arm or ALARM. Untested, though Debian may work the same as well. This process relies on the existence of /boot/extlinux/extlinux.conf Mounting the system mount /dev/nvme0n1p1 /mnt cd /mnt mkdir dev sys proc mnt Copying root files Use rsync to transfer the files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Netbsd Installation</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-netbsd-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:00:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-netbsd-installation/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Netbsd Installation Preamble Guide for installing NetBSD on the Pinebook Pro including the installation of packages, setting up networking, and other quality of life changes.&#xA;Setting Up The System Assumptions You&amp;#39;ve wrote the netbsd image to your microsd/emmc You&amp;#39;ve booted into the system If you have problems booting from the microsd card, try disabling the emmc chip. It used to be the case that you were only able to boot from microsd if the chip was disabled.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Keyboard Firmware Update</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-keyboard-firmware-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 15:59:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-keyboard-firmware-update/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Keyboard Firmware Update Preamble This is a verbatim copy of the directions written on jackhumbert&amp;#39;s git.&#xA;Installtion # compile git clone https://github.com/jackhumbert/pinebook-pro-keyboard-updater cd pinebook-pro-keyboard-updater sudo apt-get install build-essential libusb-1.0-0-dev xxd make # For ISO keyboard # step-1 sudo ./updater step-1 iso sudo reboot # after reboot, step-2 sudo ./updater step-2 iso sudo reboot # For ANSI keyboard # step-1 sudo ./updater step-1 ansi sudo reboot # after reboot, step-2 sudo .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Custom Kernel</title>
      <link>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-custom-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 15:57:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://89.147.111.130:1313/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-custom-kernel/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Custom Kernel Preamble Here&amp;#39;s how to compile tsys&amp;#39; mainline linux kernel for the Pinebook Pro. I&amp;#39;m using the &amp;#34;debian way&amp;#34; of installing the kernel. When compiling the kernel, we can tell &amp;#34;make&amp;#34; to package the binaries as multiple debian archive files (.deb). Afterward, we can simple run &amp;#34;dpkg -i .deb&amp;#34; to install it.&#xA;Setting up our enviroment Dependencies Compilation dependencies&#xA;sudo apt-get install linux-headers-$(uname -r) libncurses-dev gawk flex bison openssl libssl-dev dkms libelf-dev libudev-dev libpci-dev libiberty-dev autoconf bc fakeroot Linux Source Files</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
