<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pinebook-pro on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>https://example.org/categories/pinebook-pro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pinebook-pro on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:06:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/categories/pinebook-pro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Troubleshooting Common Issues</title>
      <link>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-troubleshooting-common-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:06:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-troubleshooting-common-issues/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Troubleshooting Common Issues Preamble A list of issues I&amp;#39;ve experienced first hand with the Pinebook Pro and resolutions.
Break/Fix Powerkey shuts off machine The powerkey is not in the most ideal locations. Edit /etc/systemd/logind.conf and change &amp;#34;HandlePowerKey=poweroff&amp;#34; to &amp;#34;HandlePowerKey=ignore&amp;#34;
Can&amp;#39;t boot at all after flashing EMMC You could either use an emmc to usb adapter to reflash your EMMC (LAME). You could use your official pine64 UART cable to see if you could fix the problem that way (EH).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Setting Up Zram</title>
      <link>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-setting-up-zram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:06:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-setting-up-zram/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Setting Up Zram Preamble ZRAM is essentially compressed memory. Your system uses some of it&amp;#39;s CPU cycles to compress redundant data into a reserved area of your ram. Think of it as swap space, but without writing to your drive.
This is how to enable zram on ALARM/Manjaro ARM
Enabling ZRAM Checking if ZRAM is supported $ insmod | grep zram Output: zram ????? ? If you get similar results, zram should be supported.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Write to Spit Flash</title>
      <link>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-write-to-spi-flash/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:03:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-write-to-spi-flash/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Write to Spit Flash Preamble Directions for flashing a custom bootloader to internal Pinebook Pro&amp;#39;s SPI Flash chip. This makes it it unnecessary to have boot code on the emmc or microsd, enabling full NVME boot. NVME boot extremely is hit or miss.
Be prepared to recover your broken SPI flash if an error occurs. When a binary is written to the SPI flash, the SPI flash will be what chooses which drives to boot from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Use Nvme as Root</title>
      <link>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-use-nvme-as-root/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:02:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-use-nvme-as-root/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Use Nvme as Root Preamble Directions on using the Pinebook Pro&amp;#39;s NVME as a root partition and the EMMC as
Moving root partitions Assumptions You have an NVME drive installed and formatted with a single EXT4 partition Running Manjaro Arm or ALARM. Untested, though Debian may work the same as well. This process relies on the existence of /boot/extlinux/extlinux.conf Mounting the system mount /dev/nvme0n1p1 /mnt cd /mnt mkdir dev sys proc mnt Copying root files Use rsync to transfer the files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Netbsd Installation</title>
      <link>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-netbsd-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 16:00:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-netbsd-installation/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Netbsd Installation Preamble Guide for installing NetBSD on the Pinebook Pro including the installation of packages, setting up networking, and other quality of life changes.
Setting Up The System Assumptions You&amp;#39;ve wrote the netbsd image to your microsd/emmc You&amp;#39;ve booted into the system If you have problems booting from the microsd card, try disabling the emmc chip. It used to be the case that you were only able to boot from microsd if the chip was disabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Keyboard Firmware Update</title>
      <link>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-keyboard-firmware-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 15:59:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-keyboard-firmware-update/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Keyboard Firmware Update Preamble This is a verbatim copy of the directions written on jackhumbert&amp;#39;s git.
Installtion # compile git clone https://github.com/jackhumbert/pinebook-pro-keyboard-updater cd pinebook-pro-keyboard-updater sudo apt-get install build-essential libusb-1.0-0-dev xxd make # For ISO keyboard # step-1 sudo ./updater step-1 iso sudo reboot # after reboot, step-2 sudo ./updater step-2 iso sudo reboot # For ANSI keyboard # step-1 sudo ./updater step-1 ansi sudo reboot # after reboot, step-2 sudo .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro Custom Kernel</title>
      <link>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-custom-kernel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 15:57:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/queztaz/pinebook-pro/pinebook-pro-custom-kernel/</guid>
      <description>Pinebook Pro Custom Kernel Preamble Here&amp;#39;s how to compile tsys&amp;#39; mainline linux kernel for the Pinebook Pro. I&amp;#39;m using the &amp;#34;debian way&amp;#34; of installing the kernel. When compiling the kernel, we can tell &amp;#34;make&amp;#34; to package the binaries as multiple debian archive files (.deb). Afterward, we can simple run &amp;#34;dpkg -i .deb&amp;#34; to install it.
Setting up our enviroment Dependencies Compilation dependencies
sudo apt-get install linux-headers-$(uname -r) libncurses-dev gawk flex bison openssl libssl-dev dkms libelf-dev libudev-dev libpci-dev libiberty-dev autoconf bc fakeroot Linux Source Files</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
